Harish Sista (He/Him)

Authorized to work for any employer (Greencard in process)

(201) 310-5683 hsista@stevens.edu 2642 28th St, Apt 4F Astoria, NY-11102

SUMMARY

Ph.D. Candidate researching in ML and NLP with 7+ years of experience working with ML models, Big Data, and Cloud Computing platforms and 2+ years of experience working in a professional environment. Spearheaded an Evidence Extraction and Fact Verification model using Prompt Engineering and tested it with various LLMs. Invented a Black Box Optimization model for online hyperparameter fine-tuning, significantly enhancing model performance in real-time applications.

SKILLS

Programming Languages	AI Tools	LLMs	Data Engineering	Cloud Platforms	Research Interests
PythonSQLNoSQLC++JavaSwiftHTML	 PyTorch HuggingFace TensorFlow SciKitlearn NumPy Pandas Matplotlib Seaborn 	 GPT LLAMA BLOOM BERT	 AWS EC2 FireWorks AI Lightning AI Data Pipelines Data Augmentation 	AWSGoogle CloudGITHeroku	 NLP Generative AI AutoML Data Science

EDUCATION

Ph.D. in Machine Learning (Computer Engineering department)	01/2018 - Present
Stevens Institute of Technology, Hoboken	
M.Eng. in Software Engineering (Electrical Engineering department)	01/2014 - 12/2015
Stevens Institute of Technology, Hoboken	
B.Eng. in Electronics and Communication Engineering	08/2009 - 05/2013
M.V.S.R Engineering College, Hyderabad, TG, India	

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Infinity Lab, Stevens Institute of Technology - Hoboken, NJ

01/2018 - Present

- Work with various LLMs to address the challenges of Fact Verification using Prompt Engineering, Text Generation, Classification and Evidence Extraction Tasks.
- Built various Python Libraries using Multiprocessing to work efficiently with big datasets.
- Surveyed and implemented various Attention Networks, DNNs and Generative Models to perform NLP tasks of Data Extraction, Modeling, Regression, Ranking, and Classification.
- Collaborated in creating various Scientific, social media, and Misinformation Datasets.
- Developed an AI based iOS application to perform MoCA test for early detection of Alzheimer's.
- Organized and maintained hardware and software for the department Lab-Server and built a personal Machine Learning RIG.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant, Stevens Institute of Technology - Hoboken, NJ

10/2018 - 09/2019

- Created a chemistry literature dataset for the purpose of similarity search with search queries.
- Preprocessed the dataset, using PDF conversion tools and NLTK library to remove the noise.
- Produced a Novel Generative Ranking Model using Topic Modeling and KeyPhrase analysis, to extract most relevant papers related to the search query.

AI Engineer/iOS Developer, Fresh Digital Group - NY, NY

07/2016 - 06/2017

- Collaborated with Content Writers and Creative Team to individually design and deploy 30 chat applications for Amazon-Alexa which won appreciation from tech newsletters.
- Developed various iOS, iMessage and tvOS applications in conjunction with several teams.
- Helped company obtain a preferred partnership with Amazon-Alexa and launching partnership with Microsoft-Cortana.

CERTIFICATIONS

Databases and SQL for Data Science with Python – IBM, Coursera

09/09/2024

Foundations of Objective-C App Development – University of California, Irvine